# Santiago Gabriel Alaniz

**Developer** 

**Río Cuarto, Córdoba, Argentina** | Santiagoemprendedor9@gmail.com | +54 358 4024726 https://react-portfolio-sankku.vercel.app/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/santiagogalaniz/

#### Skills

I am a self-taught and committed person with solid front-end knowledge of React, ES6+, HTML5, CSS3+, Typescript, Webpack, Redux, MERN, Agile Software Development (Scrum & Kanban), and TDD. Strong understanding of design principles UI/UX, CSS (Sass, JSS), Pixel Perfect and Responsive Design. Experienced in backend with NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, and Python.

- Strengths: Oral and written communication | Reliable and Consistent | Committed to Lifelong Learning
- Languages: Native: Spanish | Proficient: English

## Work Experience

## **Upwork** / FREELANCER

DEC 2021 - PRESENT (USA-LATAM)

- Deployed 100% responsive websites using JavaScript & React
- Familiarized with **CI/CD** integrations
- Apply **TDD** using MochaJS and reach 85% coverage on a system that did not have tests implemented
- Created a social media project with the **MERN** stack
- Engineered and restructured different websites UX/UI using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and FIGMA.
- Tested and debugged Code with TDD, Terminal and Jest
- Leverage Knowledge: **React**, **Python**, **JavaScript**, **TypeScript**, **GIT/Github**, deployment environments, APIs

#### **ASD Studios** / DEVELOPER

2019 - 2020 (Córdoba, Argentina)

- Implement agile methodologies (Scrum) to improve team productivity in a 30% of work volume
- Re-created an interactive website from scratch improving 127% of the performance in the browsers.
- Familiarized with teamwork and the way a team needs to be coordinated for an effective performance
- Designed and produced more than 10 characters for a videogame (layouts)
- Writing code to implement the game's features, mechanics, and functionality with **Python** & **UE4**, **Blueprints**
- Leverage Knowledge: **React**, **Python**, **JavaScript**, **TypeScript**, **Machine Learning**, **GIT/Github** for teamwork, workflow, and organization of simultaneous tasks

#### Education

**CESSI #SéProgramar** Fundamentals of Programming (2021-2022)| **#YoProgramo** Full-Stack Bootcamp (in progress). Self-taught with **+10 Certificates of Completion** | Linkedin Learning, HackerRank, Udemy & Other Platforms (2020-present)

Senior Master Builder (Architecture) | Implement mathematics and logic to solve problems, improved my creativity and my cooperation with different perspectives and methods | IPET 259 Colegio Industrial | Argentina (2020)

### **Projects**

- Deployed more than 30 personal projects 100% responsive using differents designs patterns, methodologies and paradigms (Clean Architecture, functional paradigm, imperative paradigm, POO)
- Good practices (Git, SEO, Folder management and structures)
- Reinforced my knowledge of the basic concepts of web design, compatibility and development.